Guide to the Danny Wilcox Frazier Photographs, 2003-2006 RL.11129
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Danny Wilcox Frazier photographs
2003-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Frazier, Danny, 1970-
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
RL.11129
3 Linear Feet 2 boxes; 25 items
Collection comprises twenty-five black and white gelatin silver 16x20 inch exhibit prints, representing a larger body of work on contemporary Iowa rural culture. The images portray a changing Midwest of vanishing towns and transformed landscapes. Scenes include cemeteries, slaughterhouses, farms, abandoned grain elevators, and fields. Individuals inhabiting the scenes include young people at leisure, fishermen on the Mississippi, hunters in fields, veterans on Memorial Day, Amish families, as well as more recent arrivals to Iowa, Lubavitcher Hasidic Jews at prayer and migrant workers in the fields and at home. The prints are housed in exhibit mats. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises twenty-five black-and-white gelatin silver 16x20 inch exhibit prints, representing a larger body of work by Danny Wilcox Frazier on contemporary Iowa rural culture. The images portray a changing Midwest of vanishing towns and transformed landscapes. Scenes include cemeteries, slaughterhouses, farms, abandoned grain elevators, and fields. Individuals inhapbiting the scenes include young people at leisure, fishermen on the Mississippi, hunters in fields, veterans on Memorial Day, Amish families, as well as more recent arrivals to Iowa, Lubavitcher Hasidic Jews at prayer and migrant workers in the fields and at home. The prints are arranged in exhibit number order, and are housed in hinged window mats.
The prints were featured in an exhibit entitled Driftless: Photographs from Iowa at Duke University in 2007. The term "Driftless" refers to a geological area of the Midwest untouched by glaciers. A recording of the artist's talk is available through the online exhibit.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Biographical Note
Danny Wilcox Frazier (b. 1971) is a documentary photographer based in the Midwest. His book, DRIFTLESS: PHOTOGRAPHS FROM IOWA, was published by Duke University Press in 2007, and won the Duke University Center for Documentary Studies/Honickman Book Prize in Photography.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Danny Wilcox Frazier photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2007.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Black-and-white photographs; Farms -- Iowa -- Pictorial works; Farmers -- Iowa; Iowa -- Pictorial works; Iowa -- Social life and customs; Rural population -- Iowa; Middle West -- Pictorial works; Driftless Area -- Pictorial works; Gelatin silver prints; Documentary Photography -- United States; Migrant agricultural laborers -- Iowa; Migrant workers -- Iowa -- Pictorial works; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Rainstorm, Iowa City, 2004 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-01)
- A young girl dreams of becoming a summer festival queen like her older sister, Conesville, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-02)
- Cemetery, St. Michael's Church, Holbrook, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-03)
- Shooting bottles along the Iowa River, Johnson County, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-04)
- Slaughterhouse, Solon, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-05)
- Bull rider and farmhand Rusty Caudle, North Liberty, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-06)
- Sunlight across an open field, central Iowa, 2004 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-07)
- An Old Order Amish family walks to church on Easter Sunday, Washington County, 2005 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-08)
- Gabriel Stutzman, the youngest of nine children raised by his Beachy Amish parents on the family's farm, Kalona, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-09)
- Migrant workers endure long hours bent over while harvesting watermelon, Conesville, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-10)
- Sunrise, Yellow River State Forest, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-11)
- At Jumping Rock, a notorious party spot along the Iowa River, North Liberty, 2003 (Box 1, Print RL-11129-P-12)
- Gabriel Stutzman and his brother Karlin collect firewood for the wood-burning furnace that heats their home, Kalona, 2003 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-13)
- Deer hide rotting inside a wheelbarrow, Kalona, 2003 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-14)
- Grain elevator, Frytown, 2003 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-15)
- Grain elevator and abandoned train, Lake Park, 2004 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-16)
- Guns are checked as snowfall limits visibility, opening day of deer season, near Kalona, 2005 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-17)
- Snow storm, Hills, Iowa, 2004 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-18)
- Hot Body Contest, Ottumwa, 2004 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-19)
- Latino residents share drinks on a summer evening, Conesville, 2003 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-20)
- Wedding day, Conesville, 2006 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-21)
- Lubavitcher Hasidic Jews praying, Postville, Iowa, 2003. Lubavitcher Hasidic Jews bought a closed meatpacking plant in Postville, converting it into a kosher slaughterhouse (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-22)
- Members of VFW Post 6414, Memorial Day, Riverside, 2003 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-23)
- A migrant worker rests after a fourteen-hour day in the fields, Conesville, 2003 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-24)
- Dirt road, near Lone Tree, 2003 (Box 2, Print RL-11129-P-25)